Medbh McGuckian papers, 1964-2006
Emory University
- Writings by others, Series 3; Box 31 - Box 38
  - Writings about Medbh McGuckian, Subseries 3.1; Box 31 - Box 32a
    - Broom, Sarah, Image and Symbol in the Poetry of Medbh McGuckian, thesis submitted for M.A. in English at the University of Leeds, 1995, TS (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Eberle, Wendy J., Painting a Pictographic Language, Beyond Sound Boundaries: Medbh McGuckian's Poetic Making, Centre for Comparative Literature, University of Toronto, 1995, TS (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Farago, Borbala, "Waking in the Separate Mouth"-The Muses of Medbh McGuckian, 1997, TS (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Fielding, Maureen, "'A threader / Of double-stranded words': Trauma and Testimony in Medbh McGuckian's Poetry," Dissertation chapter, TS (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Fyfe, Anne-Marie, "Presiding Spirits: Medbh McGuckian," Interview, 2006, email (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Gonzalez, Alexander G., "An Introduction to Reading Medbh McGuckian's Poetry: Close Analysis of Six Poems from The Flower Master," TS (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Hauschild, Sabine, Variations of the Self-Identity in the Poems of Medbh McGuckian, Thesis, 1997, TS (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Hehir, Niamh, "Unravelling the Line: A Study of Medbh McGuckian's Poetry," TS (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Hobbs, John, Conversations with Medbh McGuckian, Interview, 1995 (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - Holmsten, Elin, "Double Doors: An Interview with Medbh McGuckian," 2004, TS (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - Jahrling, Barbara, An Island Within the Island: Medbh McGuckian's Repossession of Language, Land and Soul in the "Ulster Plantation," thesis submitted for M.A. in English at Sonoma State University, 1992, with TLS. [1 of 4] (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - Jahrling, Barbara, An Island Within the Island: Medbh McGuckian's Repossession of Language, Land and Soul in the "Ulster Plantation," [2 of 4] (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - Jahrling, Barbara, An Island Within the Island: Medbh McGuckian's Repossession of Language, Land and Soul in the "Ulster Plantation,"" [3 of 4] (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Jahrling, Barbara, An Island Within the Island: Medbh McGuckian's Repossession of Language, Land and Soul in the "Ulster Plantation," [4 of 4] (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Jahrling, Barbara, Medbh McGuckian: An Ulsterwoman in Search of Neutral Ground, American Conference for Irish Studies, University of the Pacific, 1991, TS (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Joffe, Heidi, "Painting Houses," TS (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Kelly, Sylvia, "Bereft of My Flowers" - Iconography and Androgyne in Medbh McGuckian's Poetry, TS (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Ludwig, Jenny, "Like Theseus Through the Maze" [review of The Soldiers of Year II], TS (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Modia, María Jesús Lorenzo, "'Because God is forbidden to perform miracles in this place': Medbh McGuckian's Sense of History," TS (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Modia, María Jesús Lorenzo, Interview with Medbh McGuckian, 2003, email (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Morris, Sawnie, "Under the North Window: An Interview with Medbh McGuckian," TS [with TLS, 16 April 1998 and 17 April 2000, from Sawnie Morris] (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - Murphy, Shane, "A Code of Images": Northern Irish Centos, TS (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Murphy, Shane, Collections of Words: Medbh McGuckian's Palimpsests, TS (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Murphy, Shane, A Dove Involving a Whole Nation, TS and Proof (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - Murphy, Shane, Plagiaristic or Palimpsestic?: The Poetry of Medbh McGuckian, TS (Box 32, Folder 13)
    - Murphy, Shane, Writing in the Shit: The Northern Irish Poet and Authority, TS (Box 32, Folder 14)
    - Ó Conghalaigh, Tarlac, "The Betrayed North of My Soul" [review of Captain Lavender], TS (Box 32, Folder 15)
    - O'Connor, Laura, "Comhra: Medbh McGuckian and Nuala Ní Dhomhnaill," TS (Box 32, Folder 16)
    - Paul, Maggie, "Against Erasure: The Poetry of Eavan Boland and Medbh McGuckian," TS (Box 32, Folder 17)
    - Privas, Virginie, Interview with Medbh McGuckian, 2004, TS (Box 32, Folder 18)
    - Raney, Johannah, Muses and Fuses: An explication of "Timed Chess" and an interview with Medbh McGuckian in her office at Queens University, 1. 12. 95, 1995, TS (Box 32, Folder 19)
    - Roesler, Sarah L., Ireland's Hidden Tradition: Contemporary Irish Female Poets, Honors Thesis and Richter Project, 1995, TS (Box 32, Folder 20)
    - Sered, Danielle, Interview with Medbh McGuckian, 1998, TS [includes photocopy of the interview's publication in Nua: Studies in Contemporary Irish Writing, Spring 1998/Autumn 1999 and ALS, n.d., from Danielle Sered to McGuckian] (Box 32, Folder 21)
    - Sullivan, Moynagh, "Joking with the Critically Serious: McGuckian's Comic Oeuvre," TS (Box 32a, Folder 1)
    - Tan, Kathy-Ann, 'The Paper on Which My Gold was Written': Motherhood and writing in the poems of Medbh McGuckian, TS (Box 32a, Folder 2)
    - Thompson, Skip, Feminist Recovery Work and Women's Poetry in Ireland, University of Notre Dame, 1997, TS (Box 32a, Folder 3)
    - Wills, Clair, Obscurity in Medbh McGuckian, TS (Box 32a, Folder 4)
    - Wills, Clair, Review of On Ballycastle Beach, TS (Box 32a, Folder 5)
    - Untitled critical essays on McGuckian's poetry, TS (Box 32a, Folder 6)
    - Untitled critical essays on McGuckian's poetry, TS (Box 32a, Folder 7)
    - Untitled interviews with McGuckian, TS (Box 32a, Folder 8)
  - Other prose by others, Subseries 3.2; Box 33
    - Brandes, Rand, "Seamus Heaney's White Goddess: Mother, Muse, or Monster?" TS (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Brown, John, In the Chair: Interviews with Poets from the North of Ireland, TS [with ALS, n.d., from John Brown] (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Carlisle, R.A., Judgement Betrayed, MS novel [1 of 4] (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Carlisle, R.A., Judgement Betrayed, MS novel [2 of 4] (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Carlisle, R.A., Judgement Betrayed, MS novel [3 of 4] (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Carlisle, R.A., Judgement Betrayed, MS novel [4 of 4] (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Conlon, Evelyn, Reaction to the Field Day Anthology (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Drexel, John, The Heaven of Lost Futures (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Fitzgerald, Anne, "Carson's Inferno," TS (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Haines, John, "Poetry Chronicle," TS (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - Keery, Sam, "Irishness," TS (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - Longley, Edna, "Thought for the Day" (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - Longley, Edna, "Review of Trio," BBC (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - McGahern, John, Today and Yesterday in N. Ireland, TS (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - McGuckian, John, "Sean Quixote's Mystic Wound: Alma Mater II" [review of John Montague's Time in Armagh], TS (Box 33, Folder 15)
    - McGuinness, Frank, Today and Yesterday in Northern Ireland: Summer, TS (Box 33, Folder 16)
    - McNamee, Eoin, The Last of Deeds, novel, MS (Box 33, Folder 17)
    - Morrison, Danny, "On the Back of the Swallow," short story, TS (Box 33, Folder 18)
    - Murphy, Shane, "Friel and Heaney: Setting the Island Story Straight," proof (Box 33, Folder 19)
    - Williams, Fionnuala, The Outlaw in Irish Tradition, TS (Box 33, Folder 20)
    - Unidentified radio scripts (Box 33, Folder 21)
    - Untitled prose (Box 33, Folder 22)
  - Poems by others, Subseries 3.3; Box 34 - Box 38
    - Agee, Chris, "Thistledown," "Mandelstam," "Burning Cedar," "Peredelkind," "Offing," and "From Summer Grapes," TS [with TLS, 29 November 1999, from Chris Agee] (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Art et Gwenaël, "L'Exclu" and "Abhainn an Átha 'La Rivière du Gué,'" TS (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Carson, Ciaran, Poetry fragments, MS (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Carson, Ciaran, "Belleek," "The Bomb Disposal," "Engraving from a Child's Encyclopedia," "The New Estate," "Stations," "To a Married Sister," TS (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Carson, Ciaran, "Smithfield," "Summer of 1955," "Gifts," "Africa," "The Rosary Rally," TS [with ALS, undated, from Ciaran Carson] (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Cartarescu, Mircea, "The Beastm" "When You Need Love," "Little Elegy," TS [with TLS, 12 June 1993, from Cartarescu to Dennis] (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Connor, Noel, illustrations accompanying poems for Confounded Language: Nine Poems by Nine Irish Writers, Bloodaxe Books, 1991 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Curtin, Claire, "Gertrude in Transit" and "Closing the Season with Gertrude," TS (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Dickinson, Emily, "There's Been A Death...," proof [See Subseries 2.1: On Ballycastle Beach, "What Does Early Mean?"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - Drexel, John, "More of a Departure," TS (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Drexel, John, "From a Dictionary of Lost Causes," "Starting from Anywhere," "Keeping to Myself," "Ovid's Pibroch," "Commutations (II)," "Reassurance," "Astrologies," Photocopies and TS (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - Drexel, John, "Virginia Woolf at Giggleswick," TS (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - Duinker, Arjen, "Equivalents" and "Rounded Up and Rounded Down," fax (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - Fitzgerald, Anne, "Asylum Seekers," "Sanctuary," "Out of This World," "No True Road," "Misadventure," "Death of a Friendship," "Home," "Remote Control," TS (Box 34, Folder 13)
    - Fitzpatrick, Jackie, "Christmas in Jail," MS (Box 34, Folder 14)
    - Gallagher, Tess, "All of Us There," "Bannfoot," "Mere Mere," "Renaissance," "Diary," "Canada," "Boa Island," "Indenture," "Mapping," "Samhain," "The Aspective State," TS (Box 34, Folder 15)
    - Gallagher, Tess, "Cougar Meat," TS (Box 34, Folder 16)
    - Gallagher, Tess, "The Story of a Citizen," TS (Box 34, Folder 17)
    - Gallagher, Tess, untitled (Box 34, Folder 18)
    - Gerhardt, Ida, "De Teruggewezen Gave" and "Verwachting," TS (Box 34, Folder 19)
    - Higgins, Rita Ann, "The Flute Girl's Dialogue," proof [See Subseries 2.1: Shelmalier, "The Plague Song"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - Hughes, Art, "Lament," "The Magpie," "The Mer-Lady's Lexicon," "A Remarkable Revelation," "Salutation for an Unbaptised Mer-Child," "The Pink Lily," "Armchair," "Morning," "An Eye of Light," "A Gift," "Morning Haze," "The Spell," TS (Box 34, Folder 20)
    - Kantchev, Nikolai, Night-Watchman of the Dawn (Box 34, Folder 21)
    - Kantchev, Nikolai, Selected Poems (Box 34, Folder 22)
    - Kennelly, Brendan, extracts from The Book of Judas (proof copy) (Box 34, Folder 23)
    - Larmour, Miles, Tieyms! A Poem in Three Parts (Box 34, Folder 24)
    - Lojek, Helen, "Distance," TS (Box 34, Folder 25)
    - Longley, Michael, "The Flock," "Night Time," "Broken Dishes," "The War Graves," "The Altar-Cloth," "The Evening Star," "A Carol," TS (Box 34, Folder 26)
    - Longley, Michael, "The Iron Bird," "The Exhibit," "Persephone," TS (Box 34, Folder 27)
    - Longley, Michael, "January 12, 1996," "The Choughs," "The Evening Star," "The Mustard Tin," "The White Swallow," "San Rocco," "The Bullet Hole," "Pascoli's Portrait," "The Waterfall," "The Shaker Barn," TS (Box 34, Folder 28)
    - Longley, Michael, "The Quilt," "The Design," "The Snow Leopard," "A Sprig of Bay," "The Daffodils," "The Mustard Tin," "Birds & Flowers," "The Waterfall" [from The Weather in Japan], TS (Box 34, Folder 29)
    - Longley, Michael, "The Sunburst," "The Yellow Teapot," "The Hut," "Remembering the Poets," "The Eleven Plus," "Lone Wolf," TS (Box 34, Folder 30)
    - Mahon, Derek, "Brecht in Svendborg," TS (Box 34, Folder 31)
    - Mac Lochlainn, Gearóid, "Mo Chara ar Chuairt," "Rogha an File," "Newgrange," "Cainteoir Dúchais Eile," TS and photocopies [with TLS, 24 January 2000, from Gearóid Mac Lochlainn] (Box 34, Folder 32)
    - McBreen, Joan, "Bog-Cotton," TS (Box 34, Folder 33)
    - McBreen, Joan, "Hibernus" and "Willows," TS (Box 34, Folder 34)
    - McBreen, Joan, "One for Sorrow," TS (Box 34, Folder 35)
    - McBreen, Joan, "What We Have to Offer," TS (Box 34, Folder 36)
    - McBreen, Joan, "The Wisteria in the Courtyard of Dromore House," "The Half-Heard Lament," "The Bible Garden," TS (Box 34, Folder 37)
    - McBreen, Joan, The Woman in the Yellow Dress, with 2 loose poems and a note asking for McGuckian's help (Box 34, Folder 38)
    - McGuigan, J., "Gunfire," MS (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - McMahan, Trevor, "The Fool's Soliloquy," TS (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Mead, Jane, Concerning That Prayer I Cannot Make (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Montague, John, "Windharp," Proof [See Subseries 2.1: Portrait of Joanna, "Tulips" (OP1)] (Box -, Folder -)
    - Morrison, D.G., "Reflections," TS (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Morrissey, Sinéad, "China," TS (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Muldoon, Paul, "Duffy's Circus," Proof [See Subseries 2.1: The Flower Master and Other Poems, "The Flower Master" (OP2)] (Box -, Folder -)
    - Ní Dhomhnaill, Nuala, "TOIRCHEAS I-VI," TS (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Ó Conghalaigh, Tarlac, Miscellaneous poetry, MS and TS (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - O'Connor, Clairr, untitled (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - O'Connor Clairr, When You Need Them, TS (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - O'Hagan, Felim, "Child of the North," "Her Struggle in His Story," "A History of Prisoners," "Whose Guilt for Four Innocents?" TS (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - O'Hagan, Sheila, The Peacock Eye (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Richards, Peter, Oubliette, TS [with TLS, 8 September 2000, from Brian Henry] (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - Ross, Bernadette, Private Words in Public (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - Ryder, Joe, "Alzheimer's," TS (Box 35, Folder 14)
    - Sewell, Frank, Miscellaneous Poetry, TS [includes "TV Poets!," "A file such as I," "A poet's instructions to his latest," "Café Mozart," "Crumlin-," "Encounter," "Everything changes although it's stone," "Falling out," "Hands on a beach," "In Milltown Graveyard," "I still wear the watch you bought me," "I've had it," "Lift," "Madame Elena, 30th Avenue," "Miaow-hoot, hoot-miaow," "Nothing I got from you that wasn't broken," "Not knowing where you stand," "Old people," "Once upon a time," "The life-restoring Art in, between," "Pain you can depend on," "Rebel songs," "River deep, mountain high," "STOP!," "Surprise," "Too much," "The Muse," "The poet hides his tail in company," "TO MY LOVE WITH ALL MY LOVE FOREVER," "UnIrish poetry," "Walking the dog," "When exactly was it," and "Your pelt pyjamas"] (Box 35, Folder 15)
    - Simmons, James, "Ballycastle," TS (Box 35, Folder 16)
    - Simmons, Janice Fitzpatrick, Atlantic Shallows (Box 35, Folder 17)
    - Simmons, Janice Fitzpatrick, "For Medbh," TS (Box 35, Folder 18)
    - Simmons, Janice Fitzpatrick, "November 1993," TS (Box 35, Folder 19)
    - Simmons, Janice Fitzpatrick, Settler (Box 35, Folder 20)
    - Takahashi, Mutsuo, Beyond the Hedge: New and Selected Poems, translated by Mitsuko Ohno and Frank Sewell, TS (Box 35, Folder 21)
    - Taylor, Pat, "The Poet," TS (Box 35, Folder 22)
    - Thill, Hans, Miscellaneous poetry, TS [with TLS, 3 December 1997 and 21 April 1999, from Hans Thill] (Box 35, Folder 23)
    - Wichert, Sabine, Deposits, TS (Box 35, Folder 24)
    - Wichert, Sabine, Tin Drum Country (Box 35, Folder 25)
    - Wyley, Edna, "Diary of a Fatman," TS (Box 35, Folder 26)
    - Unsorted poems by others (Box 36, Folder 1-8)
    - Unsorted poems by others (Box 37, Folder 1-7)
    - Unsorted poems by others (Box 38, Folder 1-6)
- Personal files, Series 4; Box 39 - Box 48: Folder 3, OP4
  The series consists of personal files of Medbh McGuckian including diaries and subject files. Of particular interest in subseries 4.1 are McGuckian's personal diaries. The diaries (1965-1986) contain brief descriptions of and thoughts on daily events as well as appointments, addresses, poetry transcriptions, and quotations.
  Subseries 4.2, subject files contain printed material and correspondence relating to specific individuals, such as Seamus Heaney and Tess Gallagher, and organizations such as Aosdana, The Northern Ireland Arts Council, Queen's University Belfast, and Fortnight.
  Organized into two subseries: (4.1) Personal and family items and (4.2) Subject files.
  - Personal and family items, Subseries 4.1; Box 39 - Box 39a
    Arranged in alphabetical order by record type.
    - Curriculum vitae and recommendations (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Day calendar, August 1990-August 1991 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Day calendar, August 1992-August 1993 [also contains poetry notes] (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Day calendar, August 1993-August 1994 [also contains poetry notes] (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Day calendar, August 1994-August 1995 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Day calendar, August 1995-August 1996 [also contains poetry notes] (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Day calendar, 2000 (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Diary, 1965, 1967, 1969-73 [also contains notes, a talk on the poetry industry-teaching poetry, and other writing] (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Diary, The Queen's University of Belfast, 1967-1968 (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Diary, The Queen's University of Belfast, 1968-1969 (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - Diary, The Queen's University of Belfast, 1969-1970 (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - Diary, Ballycastle, n.d., ca 1960's (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - Diary, The Queen's University of Belfast, 1970-1971 (Box 39, Folder 13)
    - Diary, The Queen's University of Belfast, 1972-1973 [also contains notes and poetry fragments] (Box 39a, Folder 1)
    - Diary, The Queen's University of Belfast, 1973-1974 [also contains addresses and a small amount of notes and poetry fragments] (Box 39a, Folder 2)
    - Diary, Northern Ireland Diary, 1984 [also contains addresses and a small amount of notes and poetry fragments] (Box 39a, Folder 3)
    - Diary, The Career Teachers' Organisation, 1985 [also contains addresses and small amount of notes and poetry fragments] (Box 39a, Folder 4)
    - Diary, The Career Teachers' Organisation, 1986 [also contains addresses, notes, and substantial fragments of poetry] (Box 39a, Folder 5)
    - Driving licence (Box 39a, Folder 6)
    - Financial papers (Box 39a, Folder 7)
    - Financial papers (Box 39a, Folder 8)
    - Financial papers (Box 39a, Folder 9)
    - Official poll cards (Box 39a, Folder 10)
    - Passport (Box 39a, Folder 11)
    - School and college papers (Box 39a, Folder 12)
    - Travel documents (Box 39a, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous personal and family items (Box 39a, Folder 14)
  - Subject files, Subseries 4.2; Boxes 40 - Box 48: Folder 3; OP 4
    - Aósdana (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Aósdana (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Aósdana (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Aósdana (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Aósdana (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Aósdana (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Aósdana (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - Aósdana (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Aósdana (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Arts Council (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Arts Council (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Arts Council (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Arts Council (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Arts Council (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Arvon Foundation (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Ballycastle (geographical and historical information) (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Ballycastle (geographical and historical information), preliminary sketch (Box OP4)
    - BBC (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Belfast Festival at Queens (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Belfast Festival at Queens, 2000 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Children's artwork (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Conference/seminar materials (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Conference/seminar materials (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - Conference/seminar materials (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - Conference/seminar materials (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Conlon, Evelyn (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Cultural Relations Committee (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Cultural Relations Committee (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Eric Gregory Award winners (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - "Finnegans Awake" Irish Literary Festival, May 2000 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Fortnight (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Fortnight (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Fortnight (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - Fortnight (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Fortnight (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Fortnight (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Freeman, Barbara (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Gallagher, Tess (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - The Grateful Muse (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - The Grateful Muse (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - The Grateful Muse (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - The Grateful Muse (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - The Grateful Muse (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - The Grateful Muse (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - The Grateful Muse (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Heaney, Seamus (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - International IMPAC Dublin Literary Award, 2001 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Irish Times-Aer Lingus Literature Awards (later Irish Times Literary Awards) (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - Irish Writers' Union (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - The Linen Hall Library (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - The Linen Hall Library [includes the Annual Report, 1994, 1996, 1998] (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - The Linen Hall Library [includes The Linen Hall Review, issues from Autumn 1984, Winter 1984/1985, Spring 1985, Autumn 1995, Autumn 1986, Summer 1988, Winter 1990] (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - The Linen Hall Library [includes The Linen Hall Review, issues from Autumn 1991, Winter 1991, Spring 1992, Autumn 1992, Winter 1993, Spring 1994, Spring 1995] (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - Poetry International Rotterdam (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - Poetry Ireland (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - Poetry Workshop (Box 46, Folder 10)
    - Publishing Contacts List (Box 46a, Folder 1)
    - The Pushkin Prizes (Box 46a, Folder 2)
    - The Pushkin Prizes (Box 46a, Folder 3)
    - The Pushkin Prizes (Box 46a, Folder 4)
    - Queens University, Belfast and Armagh (Box 46a, Folder 5)
    - Queens University, Belfast and Armagh (Box 46a, Folder 6)
    - Queens University, Belfast and Armagh (Box 46a, Folder 7)
    - Queens University, Belfast and Armagh (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Queens University, Belfast and Armagh (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Queens University, Belfast and Armagh (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Prison visitations (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Publishers' catalogues including work by McGuckian (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Ratushinskaya, Irina (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - The Seamus Heaney Centre for Poetry at Queen's University Belfasy (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - Sibíla (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - Sibíla (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - Teaching Records (Box 47, Folder 10)
    - University of California, Berkeley (Box 47, Folder 11)
    - University of Ulster (Box 47, Folder 12)
    - University of Ulster (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - University of Ulster (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Yeats Summer School (Box 48, Folder 3)
- Printed material, Series 5; Box 48: Folder 4 - Box 71, OP 5-22
  The Medbh McGuckian papers include many collected publications--clippings and entire magazines and journals--with material by or about McGuckian. Subseries 5.1, Writings by McGuckian, and Subseries 5.2, Writings about McGuckian, are both arranged chronologically by type, while Subseries 5.3, Other printed material, is ordered alphabetically by title. Additional printed material relating to individuals and organizations may be found in Subseries 4.2, Subject files. Typescripts of writing by others are located in Series 3.
  Organized into three subseries: (5.1) Writings by McGuckian, (5.2) Writings about McGuckian, and (5.3) Other printed material.
  - Writings by Medbh McGuckian, Subseries 5.1; Box 48: Folder 4 - Box 56a: Folder 3; OP5
    Arranged by type of record.
    - Publications with poems, 1973 - 2005
    - "Genesis" and "Blackcurrants" in Caret, Winter 1973, p. 18-19 (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - "Marriage" in The Honest Ulsterman, March-June 1975, p. 10 (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - "Lent," "The Singer," and "Faith" in The Irish Press, October 11, 1975, p. 6 [2 copies] (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - "Subterfuge" and "Accident" in St. Stephens, 1976, p. 14 and 40 (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - "Maiden Aunt" in Fortnight, September 1978, p. 12 (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - "Today" in Ulster Tatler, January 1979, p. 32 (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - "Coins" in Northern Lights, February 1979, p. 24 (Box 48, Folder 10)
    - "Aunts" and "Inch" in Cyphers, Spring 1979, p. 1 (Box 48, Folder 11)
    - "Wife-Swapping" in Outposts, Autumn 1979, p. 6 (Box 48, Folder 12)
    - "The Cure" and "Purgatory" in The Irish Press, September 1 1979, p. 9 (Box 48, Folder 13)